I can take you into the mine as agreed.
But you'll be on your own once you're inside.
Don't worry about what happens inside.
What about what you promised me?
What I promised won't change.
But you better not play any tricks.
I wouldn't dare.
One word from you and my head is gone.
I'll handle them.
Officer.
Halt!
Papers. We're on the same side.
Officer.
We are under Colonel Matsuda's orders
to bring two translators for him to see.
Thank you, officer.
Let's go. Okay.
Masao Tahara is here.
He has seen me.
Why don't you hide first?
Mr. Meng.
Officer.
These stupid Chinese
have dug the mine to the point of collapse.
Yes.
Did you find the translators I asked for?
Yes, I did.
These are the new translators.
Hello, Officer. My surname is Xu.
Xu. Xu.
Xu.
Hurry up and find him.
Tahara Masao will be back soon.
Neither of us will be able to leave, I'm telling you.
What are you talking about?
I'm telling you,
Tahara Masao is chasing Cui Wenpei now.
He won't have time for us for a while.
If we can't find
the person we're looking for this time,
then next time,
you'll have to bring us in again.
My God!
Do you think this is a restaurant or a tavern?
You can't just come and go as you please.
You were outside just now
and almost sold me out.
Did you think I didn't notice?
Let me tell you,
if you make a fuss again this time,
believe it or not, I'll give you a grenade
and send you to hell early.
Xu, if I wanted to harm you,
would you still be standing here?
You're the boss, okay?
Hurry up and go.
Hurry up, I'll keep watch.
Go.
Ascend to the Heavenly Terrace.
Protect my life and body.
Compete on the same stage.
Calm the spirit and mind.
Mysterious realm and underworld.
Who are you?
How do you know
the rallying call of our Eighteen Strongholds?
Are you Master Six?
Yes, I am Wu Laoliu.
Which stronghold are you from?
Come.
Yuanshangfei told me.
He asked me to find you.
Yuanshangfei?
Yes.
How are the Eldest Miss and the others?
Are they all right?
They've joined the Eighth Route Army guerrilla forces.
And they are both vice-captains now.
They know you were captured and brought to the mine,
and have been trying to rescue you.
It's rare.
The Eldest Miss and Chief Yuan
still remember me.
I, Wu Laoliu, will keep it in my heart.
By the way,
do you have any plans?
I can cooperate with you.
They plan to attack the mine in a while.
When the time comes, they hope you can
organize everyone
so we can evacuate in an orderly manner.
No problem.
Half of the people in the cave
are my brothers.
As soon as I give the order,
whether it's protecting the civilians
or helping you fight the Japs,
it won't be a problem.
That's great.
With your cooperation,
we can attack from inside and outside,
and catch the Japs off guard.
Good.
That's great.
I've been holding in this anger,
and now I can finally let it out.
Although we swordsmen don't have our swords,
But our unyielding spirit remains.
Even if I die here and can't get out,
I will take a few Japanese devils down with me.
Xiaoni.
How did you get like this?
Wenpei.
I... I stole the map,
and gave it to Tianyuan Zhengxiong.
I wanted to save my dad.
I just wanted to save my dad.
Let's go.
Go back with me.
To defeat the Japs,
we must first understand
their combat techniques.
For example, the Japs excel at bayonet fighting.
That is because
they practice thousands of times a day.
Actually, the movements are very simple,
just three steps.
Lunge, parry, and block.
But under long-term rigorous training,
these skills become natural reflexes.
A half-second thrust is either fatal or crippling.
Many of my comrades
suffered a lot from the Japanese.
But the broadswords in our hands
can effectively counter their bayonet charges.
Close combat is our broadswords' strong point.
As long as we rush into
their rifle's blind spot,
we can effectively counter them.
Now we will give you a demonstration.
Watch closely.
Mr. Li.
Everyone, watch closely.
Come on.
Block, grab,
and kill.
One more time.
Come on.
Block, grab, kill.
Pair up freely
and practice.
Ying'er, Baozi.
Hurry up.
Hurry.
Old Li. Here.
Lead everyone in training.
Hurry, hurry! Okay.
The rest of you, come with me.
Yes.
Careful.
What happened to Xiaoni?
When I was evading the enemies,
I found Xiaoni among the corpses.
Quickly see how she is.
I will go find a doctor.
Baozi, get her some water and food.
Okay.
Ying,
I'll leave this to you.
Ni.
Sister,
is it really you?
Sister.
Sister,
I thought I would never,
never see you again.
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have listened to the Japanese's nonsense
and stolen your map.
Sister.
Stop talking. Don't say that.
It's good that you're back.
Nothing is more important than you coming back.
Everything else is in the past.
Sister,
it hurts so much.
I know it hurts.
Bear with it a little longer.
Wenpei has gone to find a doctor.
It'll be fine once the doctor arrives.
Sister,
there's something
I want to ask of you.
Tell me.
I'll promise you anything.
I want to ask you
not to kill my dad,
okay?
I know
this is too much to ask.
But he didn't do it willingly.
He only went down the wrong path
for me and my mom.
Sister.
You're in this condition,
and you're still pleading for him.
No matter what,
he's still my dad.
Sister, I beg you.
Please.
Sister.
Okay.
I promise you.
But you have to promise me too.
You have to stay alive, okay?
Mi.
Give this to my dad.
Tell him to stop doing bad things.
Now no one is threatening him.
Tell him to take good care of himself from now on.
If he misses me,
he can look at this necklace.
Xiaoni.
I really want to go back to Qinglong Stronghold.
I really want to eat the pears from the back mountain.
I really want
to go
home.
Ni.
Talk to me again.
Say something to me, Ni.
Ni.
Ni,
these are all your favorite foods.
This is the closest place to Qinglong Stronghold.
I hope you like it.
The Japanese devils ruined her life.
Tahara Masao killed Aunt Meixiang,
making her lose her most beloved relative.
This blood debt,
we will settle with him sooner or later.
But what we need to do right now
is to help Xiaoni
fulfill her unfulfilled wish.
Qinglong Stronghold has been occupied by the Japanese.
We can't get anywhere near it.
After Uncle Banjin died,
the secret passage is gone too.
He Xiaobian hides in the stronghold every day,
like he's dead,
with no movement at all.
How do we get close?
I thought of a way.
Come up.
Boss Cai.
Miss.
What are you doing here?
I...
Ying'er,
The method I mentioned needs his help.
What do you mean?
Wait, what do you want me to do now?
I have already risked my life
to help you once before.
Don't make me do anything dangerous again.
I have a family to support now.
If I die,
what will happen to my wife and children?
Don't panic.
It's a very simple favor this time.
Go to Qinglong Stronghold and bring Advisor He down the mountain.
That's it?
I can do that,
but that old guy,
I don't know if he will believe me.
Ying'er.
Give this to Master He.
He will follow your orders.
All right, I'll go then.
Master He.
Still in the mood to drink?
What are you doing here?
I don't recall your detective squad
having any official business in Qinglong Stronghold.
Drop the act.
We are both now
in the exact same situation.
We both work for Masao Tahara.
The difference is,
I only betrayed Huo Lang
and now act as an informant for the Japanese.
But I don't have the blood of my brothers on my hands.
You are different.
Every swordsman in Sandaoyuan
wants you dead the moment they see you.
Did you come to Qinglong Stronghold
just to talk this nonsense to me?
Of course not.
I was entrusted by someone to find you.
Someone told me to give this to you.
Ni'er.
This isn't true.
Tian Yuanzhengxiong promised me
he wouldn't hurt my daughter.
I did everything he asked me to do.
Why did he hurt my daughter?
Only you would believe the Japanese.
Do you know where we found Xiaoni?
Do you know what she went through?
Where?
We carried her out of a pile of dead bodies.
When we found her,
she was covered in wounds and on her last breath.
You caused all of this.
You killed my father,
killed so many brothers,
then my aunt, and now Xiaoni.
Even when she died, she was thinking of you, her father.
She said,
only if she dies
can you be free from any restraints.
Only then can you be a good man again.
Only then can you live in peace.
Stop talking.
Stop.
Stop it.
I just wanted to tell you all this.
You're even afraid to listen now.
What about Xiaoni?
What did she go through?
It's all my sin.
It's all my fault.
I've let every single one of you down.
Ying'er.
Kill me.
I deserve to die.
Kill you?
If you die,
will they come back to life?
I promised Xiaoni
I wouldn't kill you.
So I absolutely won't.
Ni'er.
Go.
Hurry.
The gold mining has been progressing very fast these past few days.
It looks like we'll finish
General Kurokawa's task very soon.
It's all thanks to your full supervision, Colonel,
that these Chinese laborers don't dare slack off.
However, I think we still need to
speed up our mining.
Why do you say that?
A few days ago,
I noticed Cui Wenpei around here.
Plus, Cui Wenkui of the Independent Brigade has been redeploying his troops frequently,
seemingly intending to advance towards the gold mine.
I don't think their actions are a coincidence.
They must have reached an agreement
to attack our gold mine.
With those few broken guns of the Chinese army,
they want to attack our gold mine?
It's impossible within ten miles.
Tahara, you're overthinking.
If it were a frontal assault, it wouldn't be scary.
What I fear is another sneak attack.
Our transport trucks were frequently attacked before.
That was Cui Wenpei's doing.
As the Chinese saying goes,
better safe than sorry.
That makes sense.
General Kurokawa takes this gold mine very seriously.
We can't afford any mistakes.
Tahara,
do you have any good ideas?
I think we should transport it early
and ship the gold ore to Fuyang as soon as possible,
to avoid undue delay and trouble.
You are very meticulous, Tahara.
We'll do as you suggest.
When the time comes, I'll personally escort it.
Thank you for your trouble, Colonel.
Today I overheard at the mine
that Masao Tahara and that old devil Matsui
will personally escort the gold to Luoyang.
So there will be a battle to fight.
But Matsui takes this transport very seriously.
He will personally be in charge of the escort.
They will definitely be equipped with light and heavy weapons along the way.
With our guerrillas' weapons,
it will be hard to even get close.
Once the battle comes to a stalemate...
The surrounding Japanese troops will immediately reinforce
and cut off our retreat.
We can choose to fight in Jiapigou.
Jiapigou is the only way
from Shanzhou City to Luoyang.
It is also far from the Japanese sphere of influence.
Even if Matsui and Tahara call for reinforcements,
they won't arrive for two hours.
And the treacherous terrain and dense forests there
make it perfect for an ambush.
After completing the mission,
we will have time to evacuate safely.
What about the heavy weapons of the Japanese troops?
We can ask Wenkui for help.
His independent brigade is well-equipped
and can fight against the enemy.
If we join forces,
we should be able to end the battle quickly.
Okay.
Old Xu,
you are responsible for contacting Cui Wenkui.
Okay, I'll go right away.
Colonel,
you are truly brilliant.
To predict that the Chinese army
would target our gold transport vehicle.
You sent a squadron early in the morning
to set up a sniper position south of Dawang Town,
making their ambush plan impossible.
I just don't know
if our squadron
can withstand the Chinese army's attack.
It is said that the general named Cui Wenkui
is a very formidable character.
He has fought our Imperial Army many times,
and the Imperial Army has always suffered losses.
Cui Wenkui is indeed a fierce general.
But since he left the Nationalist Party,
his ammunition and supplies have been cut off.
The hijacking of the supply truck last time
was because we were too careless,
which allowed them to succeed.
Now, this Cui Wenkui
wouldn't dare confront me head-on.
A tiger without claws,
what is there to fear?
Yes, the Colonel is right.
Lao Xu.
Did you confirm the time with Cui Wenkui?
I explained it very carefully.
I left nothing out.
Look at the time.
Why isn't his Independent Brigade here yet?
Tell me about it.
Do you think he backed out?
No.
Cui Wenkui wouldn't do that at a time like this.
He must have run into some trouble.
What now? Do we attack?
We attack. We have to.
But we can't attack head-on.
We need to outsmart them.
Baozi, stop keeping us in suspense.
Tell us how to outsmart them.
Have you all heard of 'Outsmarting the Birthday Convoy'?
Today, we'll put on a show for the Japs.
But it's been
too quiet along the way.
It's a bit unusual.
Sandaoyuan
is the active area of the Eighth Route Army guerrilla forces.
Logically, they should have heard the news,
and set up an ambush on the road.
But we haven't seen a single soul so far.
The guerrilla forces,
their weapons are too primitive.
Broadswords and crude guns
pose no threat to us at all.
If they want to hijack my transport,
they are daydreaming.
If they dare to face me in a head-on battle,
killing them
will be as easy as slaughtering pigs and cows.
Without Cui Wenkui's support,
they wouldn't have the guts.
I actually want them to show up.
Without them for entertainment,
our journey would be too boring.
We're about to leave Sandaoyuan.
I don't think the guerrilla forces will appear again.
I'm afraid the Colonel will be disappointed.
Ando, you're right again.
These pitiful Chinese people
in their own territory
are like mice.
Sneaking around every day,
they simply don't dare
to move in broad daylight.
The Eighth Route Army guerrillas may be unrefined,
but they aren't fools.
Why would they walk right into a trap?
What's the situation?
Quick.
Hurry up.
Officer, save us.
Guerrillas are attacking us.
Which unit are you from?
We are delivering documents from Mianchi to Shanzhou.
Wipe out those guerrillas.
Retreat.
Thank you for saving us, officer.
You're welcome.
We are all soldiers of the Imperial Army.
You will take the second vehicle later
to ensure your safety.
Thank you.
Bastards.
Intercept them.
Miss. Adjutant Zhu.
Brother Cai.
Where are your men?
It's way past our agreed time.
Don't mention it.
We started off according to the original plan,
but we encountered a Jap attack on the way.
It took a lot to shake them off.
What about Wenpei and Yuanshangfei?
That's what I'm here for.
Cui Wenpei and the gold transport truck
are both at our base.
It's a success.
Yes.
We succeeded.
Brothers, we succeeded.
Success, success, good.
Are they alright?
Wenpei and Yuanshangfei are both fine.
Not even a scratch.
Rest assured.
I've delivered the message,
so I'll take my leave.
Thanks for your hard work.
Okay.
Then let's fall in.
Fall in.
Let's go.
Extra food tonight.
Okay. Let's go.
Let's go.
You shoot so well. Where did you learn it?
When I was a swordsman,
I often fought with the security forces.
They obviously couldn't beat us,
so they set up ambushes secretly.
So I pay special attention to
The skill of locating by sound
is to counterattack
as quickly as possible.
I remember when I was in the stronghold,
I used to bet on drinks with my brothers.
With this skill,
I won a lot of good liquor from them.
But later, when they bet again,
they refused to include me.
When I was training in Juntong,
we had similar courses.
But none of those instructors shot as well as you do.
Teach me when you have time.
You are so skilled,
why would you need me to teach you?
What do you mean?
After all, we are comrades who have been through life and death together.
I didn't mean that.
If you really want to learn,
I'll teach you everything.
That's more like it.
Get up.
Since you help me so often,
I'll mend these clothes for you.
Brigadier Cui.
What are you laughing at?
Nothing.
Have a seat.
What are your orders, Brigadier Cui?
What are you laughing at?
Nothing.
I just came to thank you
for taking care of our Wenpei along the way.
You are too polite, Commander Cui.
Protecting the commissar is my duty.
Right.
Protecting your commissar is your duty.
Yuanshangfei.
There are no outsiders here.
Let's have a heart-to-heart talk.
You probably know
that Wenpei and I
were separated when we were young.
But did you know
that when she was little,
she was the apple of my and our father's eye?
We spoiled her
and gave her the best of everything.
I can hardly imagine over the years
how much she has suffered and endured.
Do you know that after finding her,
I wanted to give her
the best,
to give her all the best things?
As an older brother,
I should take care of her.
But a brother can't take care of her forever.
So,
I have a presumptuous request for you.
Commander, please speak.
I, Yuanshangfei, will do my best.
We were both in the Nationalist army
and have dealt with each other before.
Of course, let the unpleasant past
stay in the past.
Your character and temper,
I know.
And I approve of them.
You have to take good care of my sister for me.